译本提供&校订：SWAT1909  英文&时间轴：explosiveskull
该死
Fuck!
好了  这里有十个数字  四个空位
Okay, I've got ten numbers, four spots.
要找到四位密码
I need a four-digit code.
不
No, no, no.
该死  又怎么了？
Shit! What now?
该死
Shit.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
找线索
Clues.
该死  好吧
Shit. Okay.
没用
That's nothing.
追随光明  绿色生机
"Follow the light to greener pastures."
这是什么意思？
What does that mean? What does that mean?
光明？ 什么光明？
Light? What light?
光明  追随光明
Light. Follow the light.
绿色  绿色的书  对
Green. Green book, yeah.
绿色生机  好了
Greener pastures. Okay. Yeah, all right.
每每在历史洪流当中  见证另一人之死
"At any point in history, to watch another die,
揭开时间的伟大奥秘  同时可保你全身而退
unveils time's great mystery, while leaving you alive."
时间  一定是钟表之类的
Time. Time. Some kind of clock.
该死
Shit.
哪里有钟表？
Where's the clock?
我就没看见什么钟表
I don't see a goddamn clock!
见证另一人至死
"To watch another person die."
对  好的
Yeah. Okay, yeah.
见证另一人至死
"To watch another person die."
该死
Oh, shit!
好吧  他们的手指指着  我想想
Okay. They're pointing! Let's see.
是时间  这是钟表指针的象征  对
It's time. It's hands on a clock. Yeah.
这只手是四点  是四点
That one's four! Four o'clock!
八点
Eight.
六点
Six!
两点  就是这四个数  这是密码
Two! That's the number, that's the code!
很好  四在哪里？ 该死  快点
Okay. Where's the four? Shit. Come on.
行了  好的
All right. Okay.
好  很好
Yeah, good.
快点  八
Come on, come on! Eight!
六
Six.
天啊
Oh, my God.
在哪里？ 六
Where's the...? Six, six, six!
天啊
Oh, God!
二
Two, two!
对  好了  快点
Yeah. Okay. Come on.
快啊
Come on.
快开啊  怎么没反应？
Come on! Why isn't it working?
该死
Oh, shit.
快点
Come on.
开啊  快点  开门
Open! Come on, open!
天啊  根本就没有出口
Oh, God, there's no way out!
求你们放我出去
Please get me out!
该死  不
Shit! No!
不
No!
《密室逃生》
伊利诺伊州  芝加哥
三天前
有人听过“越盯着壶 水越不开”这句话吗？
Has anyone ever heard the saying, "A watched pot never boils"?
其实在量子领域里  这很可能是真的
Well, on a quantum scale, that may actually be true.
有人知道量子芝诺效应是什么意思吗？
Does anyone know what the quantum Zeno effect is?
一套系统在观测过程中不会发生变化
大家这会儿不太积极啊
Wow, guys, not all at once now.
一套系统在观测过程中不会发生变化
这个可能是
Well, it may well be
量子物理学是最奇特的一条理论
one of the oddest things in quantum physics.
简单来说  观测本身会致使运动静止
Simply put, observation stops movement.
原子在被观测时不会衰变
Atoms won't change while you watch them.
好了  今天就上到这里
All right, that's all the time we have.
大家好好放假吧  我们假期后再见
Have a good holiday. See you after the break.
祝你们感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving.
佐伊  能跟你说两句吗？
Zoey, can I talk to you for a minute?
我看了你那篇量子芝诺效应的论文
I read your paper on the quantum Zeno effect.
你还是希望被人倾听的
So, you want to be heard.
也愿意分享知识
You want to share what you know,
可难道只有在宿舍你才无所顾忌吗？
but only in the safety of your own dorm room?
我会试着多发言的
I'll try and speak up more.
虽然理论上减少生活当中的变量
It might seem like reducing the number of variables
似乎可以控制结果
in your life will control the outcome,
但生活并不是科学实验
but life isn't a science experiment.
你不能永远固守在自己的世界
You can't contain your world forever.
趁着放假尝试做一件你不敢做的事
Try doing one thing that scares you
好吗？
over break, okay?
好的
Okay.
杰森·沃克预留车位
雷  我是杰森  听着
Ray, it's Jason. Listen.
你想在退休前买一艘船  对吧？
You want to buy a boat by retirement, right?
你再盯着低回报率股票
Well, keep focusing on these low-beta stocks,
就只能划小皮艇了  桨还得另租
and it's going to be a rowboat with rented oars.
第一季度末股市的
By the end of the first quarter,
收益率会涨到百分之十
the market's going to see a 10-percent return,
而我能让你在出海前赚到百分之三十
while you'll be sailing away with 30.
你不会后悔的
Hey, you won't regret it.
我在你眼里像不像商界的宫城先生  查理
I must be like the Mr. Miyagi of trading to you, Charlie.
什么先生？
"Mr...?"
我的天  小子  你哪年生的？
Jesus Christ, kid, what year were you born?
这是个智慧的日本老头
He's this wise, old Japanese man
教小孩用空手道打遍儿童界无敌手
who taught a kid karate so he could beat up other kids.
阿克曼先生在一号线等你通话
Mr. Ackerman for you on line one.
赌一百块我有礼物收了
100 bucks says I'm getting a gift.
恭喜你  阿克曼先生  你在庆祝吗？
Congratulations, Mr. Ackerman. Are you celebrating?
谢谢你  谢谢  阿克曼先生
Well, thank you. Thank you, Mr. Ackerman.
不  这礼物我可不能收
No. No, no, no, I couldn't accept a gift.
私人飞机  去大溪地吗？
A private jet. To Tahiti?
你家在那里
Your home there.
去下载《龙威小子》
这样听起来才叫度周末
Now, that sounds like a hell of a weekend.
能够用筷子夹住苍蝇的人
Man who catch fly with chopstick...
做什么事都能成
accomplish anything.
你是菜鸟走了狗屎运
You, beginner luck.
打蜡
Wax on, wax off.
加里  我
Hey, Gary. I, uh...
我之前听说
I heard there was...
收银台那边现在缺个人
an opening up front at checkout.
我想升职多赚点
I could use the bump.
我不想住我妈家了
I'm trying to move out of my mom's.
她开始嫌我碍眼了
It's starting to cramp her style.
听着  我理解你的难处  孩子
Look, I feel for you, kid.
我真的理解  你知道 真的
I really do. You know, I do.
只是如果调你去前面  恐怕会影响生意
It's just putting you out front would be bad for business.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊  我就不适合
Yeah, I'm not cut out for
干伺候顾客的活儿  所以
customer service shit anyhow, so...
本
Ben...
你要放松得换个健康点的方式
you've got to find healthier ways to unwind.
出去走走  交点朋友
Go outside, make a friend.
我不是故意的  -没事  不好意思
- I didn't mean to... - It's fine, it's fine. Sorry.
好吧  谢了  加里
Yeah. Thanks, Gary.
这是邮差送来给你的
A messenger dropped this off for you.
阿克曼先生寄的
It's from Mr. Ackerman.
一点也不意外
Of course it is.
希望是特斯拉跑车的钥匙
This better be keys to a Tesla.
感谢你总能跳脱框架去思考
"For always thinking outside the box."
看来阿克曼先生不送单一麦芽威士忌
Well, it seems like Mr. Ackerman has graduated
而是改送盒子了  还是打不开的
from sending single malts to boxes that don't open.
是啊  有钱人都挺怪的
Yeah. Rich people are weird.
金钱买不来快乐
Money can't buy you happiness.
人生再苦都得自己扛  查理
You better afford your own brand of misery, Charlie.
感恩节快乐  -快什么乐  明天我还来呢
- Happy Thanksgiving. - Whatever. I'll be in tomorrow.
♪ They say sleep Is the cousin of death ♪
我没收回邀请
Hey, offer still stands.
你真的不想跟我一起回家过感恩节吗？
Are you sure you don't want to come to my family's for Thanksgiving?
谢谢你  不过  你懂的
Thank you, but, you know,
我真的不习惯跟一大家子人吃饭
big family dinners aren't really my thing.
好吧
Okay.
你知道  我真的很喜欢自己一个人待着
You know, I'm really psyched about having time to myself.
我老想试着研究
I've been wanting to take a stab
这些有关长方体的猜想  研究一辈子都行
at one of those cuboid conjectures for, like, forever.
这些猜想真的很酷
It's really cool, actually.
它们的理论就是在讲
They claim irreducibility
有三个整系数一元多项式根本是不可约的
of three univariate polynomials with integer coefficients
而如果这是真的
and if that is true,
那大数学家欧拉的完美盒子概念就不可能存在了
then Euler's concept of a perfect box can't exist.
知道吗  有时我很怀疑这些词是不是你瞎编的
You know, sometimes I wonder if you just make up words
反正你知道我不会上网去查
because you know I won't Google them.
数独游戏
别又来了
Not again.
热爱生活
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
没事  不好意思
Yeah, I'm sorry.
那我就先走了
Well, I'm out of here.
好的
Okay.
优先送达
有你的快递
Hey, this is for you.
寄件人是你的教授
It's from your professor.
等等
- Wait.
你们俩不是在一起了吧？
You guys aren't doing it, are you?
怎么会？ 没有
What? No.
那就祝你跟你的盒子玩得开心
Well, have fun playing with your... box.
再见  艾莉森
Bye, Allison.
再见
Bye.
佐伊
打开新世界大门
"Open new doors."
本
一个逃离的机会
"A chance to escape."
记住  打开谜盒得靠直觉
Remember, the puzzle box is intuitive.
暴力拆解会有危险
You don't want to force it.
枇杷  咔哒  然后
Snap, crackle, and...
我恨你
I hate you.
居然把这玩意给一个初中数学不及格的人
Give this to the guy that failed eighth grade math.
好主意  加里
Great idea, Gary.
这简直就是浪费
This is the biggest waste of...
恭喜你  获得米诺斯密室逃生的入场券
"This serves as an entry voucher for Minos Escape Rooms."
谁能率先逃出我们最具真实感的密室
"Be the first to escape our most immersive rooms yet
就能获得一万美金
and win $10,000."
报名请登录米诺斯密室逃生网站
"RSVP at minosescaperooms.com."
你好
Hi.
请问这是米诺斯大厦吗？
This is the Minos building?
应该是  -谢谢
- I think so. - Thanks.
是  吸烟会死  我知道
Yeah, it's going to kill me, I know.
你好
Hi.
我来参加密室逃生游戏
Yeah. I'm here for the escape room.
请出示证件
ID please.
伊利诺伊州驾照
阿曼达·哈珀
谢谢
Thanks.
通常男人得先请我吃饭  -我得没收你的手机
- Most guys buy me dinner first. - I need to collect your phone.
是吗？为什么？
Really? Why?
为了不让你把密室的照片发上网
You can't be Twittering pictures of the puzzles.
好吧  -请上三楼
- Okay. - Third floor.
好  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
感谢你为国效力
Thank you for your service.
麻烦别关门
Hold the door, please.
我总会再偷带一个手机
I always sneak in a second one.
在等候室里待着太无聊了
- The waiting rooms can get so boring. - Mm.
米诺斯密室逃生
等候区
太棒了
Yes!
请您就座  稍后会有人接待
Please have a seat. Someone will be with you shortly.
好吧  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
多好的欢迎礼  是吧
Quite the welcome wagon, isn't she?
太友善了
Super friendly. Heh.
你好  我叫迈克尔  叫我迈克吧
- Hey, Michael. Mike.
我叫阿曼达
- Amanda.
你叫阿曼达吗？ -是的
- Your name's Amanda? - Yeah.
这么巧啊  -怎么？
- Isn't that funny?- What?
我家以前养的狗就叫阿曼达
I had a family dog growing up named Amanda.
她很可爱  是哈士奇和科利的串儿
She was a cute, little husky-collie.
她两只眼睛颜色不一样
Two different colored eyes, actually.
非常特别  对
It was very unique. Yeah.
很酷
Cool.
是啊  确实很酷  对  但她不在了
Yeah, she was cool. Yeah, and then she died.
你知道  狗都命短
You know, dogs die.
我搭便车出了意外
Hitchhiking accident.
《属于她的香水》
那你还能打电玩吗？
Can you still play video games?
不能  不能了  兄弟  很可惜不能了
No. No, man. Unfortunately I can't,
现在我也只能跟成年的姑娘玩玩当消遣了
so I just have sex with adult women to fill the time.
好吧  -是的
- Heh. Okay. - Yeah.
打扰一下  你好
Sorry. Hi.
你好  -我们认识吗？
- Hi. - Do I know you?
不  应该不认识
No, I don't think so.
是吗？ 我真的觉得你很面熟
Really? You look really familiar to me.
你是不是上过电视什么的？
You're not on TV or something, are you?
好吧  这可要命了  你们好
Well, this is going to suck. Hi.
你好
Hey.
要签到吗？
Sign-in sheet?
用不着签到  接待员没空管我们
Yeah, don't bother. She's preoccupied.
你好吗？ 我是迈克
How are you doing? Mike.
我是本  -本
Ben. - Ben.
你也收到那盒子了  对吧？ 兄弟
I'm guessing you got a box too, huh?
《芝加哥镜报》
五人被活活烧死
对
Yeah.
《芝加哥镜报》
五人被活活烧死
打开它花了很长时间吧？
Did it take you long to open it?
《芝加哥镜报》
五人被活活烧死
打开它花了很长时间吧？
Did it take you long to open it?
我倒是没花太长时间
It didn't take me too long.
没错  我们都收到盒子了
Yeah, we all got boxes.
打开它这个关卡已经算简单的了
Opening it was the easy part.
我看那个网站发现这游戏
So, the website for this place made the games
还挺好玩的  是吧？
look pretty fun, huh?
对  基本就是把电子游戏挪到现实里了
Yeah. They're basically like real-life video games.
是吗？ 这么说
- Really? - So, you've done
你玩过这种游戏
one of these before.
我之前玩过九十三个不同的密室  对  都是大型密室
I've done 93 rooms. Yeah, all the big ones.
有战栗空间  难解谜局  地下谜城
Panic Room, Enigma, Basement...
越狱  闯空门  反锁室  当然还有禁闭屋
Breakout, Break In, Lock In. Lock Down, of course.
我还玩过各种地堡  有一战的  二战的
I've done all the bunkers: World War One, World War Two...
冷战时期的  还有《冷战二：波尔·波特的复仇》
Cold War, Cold War Two: Pol Pot's Revenge.
你们玩过什么？
What about you guys?
看来你非常擅长玩这个喽？
You must be really good at these, huh?
对  我是玩得不错
Yeah. I'm pretty good.
这不算本事
It's not cool.
知道吗  我侄子很像你
Yeah. You know, my nephew's like you.
他玩这个上瘾
He's completely obsessed. He burns through
把所有零花钱都花在密室逃生上了
all of his allowance money on escape rooms.
我来这里都是他替我报的名
He's the reason why I'm here. He signed me up.
我听说这个密室
And apparently this room was rated
被一些网友评为全国最棒的密室之一
one of the top in the country on some chat room.
对
Yeah.
我的盒子是有钱的怪客户送的
My weirdo rich client gave this to me as a gift.
不来不合适
It felt mandatory.
花钱请别人把我关到密室里这种事
Yeah, paying people to lock me in a room
我反正是没兴趣
never seemed too appealing to me.
是吗？ 那怎么改主意了？
Yeah? What changed your mind?
我是为了一万美金  -对对  我也是
- Ha, ha. Uh...$10,000. - Yeah, me too.
一万美金对我来说是很大一笔钱  你们懂
That is a big chunk of change in my book, you know?
对  我以前受过伤
Yeah. I've been driving an 18-wheeler
一直在当拖车司机
since I had this injury a while back,
但是老有新闻说会有什么自动驾驶汽车
and I've been reading about these self-driving cars.
你们懂的  我听说卡车运输业
You know. And I heard that the trucking industry's
会最先实现自动化
going to be the first one to get automated,
所以我想在
so I'm trying to just squirrel away a few nuts
被机器抢走饭碗之前多攒点钱
before the robots come to get me.
这话题太扫兴了  老兄  -这就是我的生活
- That was a real buzzkill, man. - It's just my life.
这个密室难度一定很高
This one's got to be really insane
不然不会有现金大奖  据网上说
for there to be a cash prize. The website said
至今还没有人成功逃脱
no one's been able to escape it yet.
如果我们成功了
If we're able to do that,
会有多少粉丝  你们绝对想象不到
we're going to have so much street cred. You have no idea.
那这游戏有没有什么规则？
Are there rules and regulations? What?
只要在规定时间内逃出来就行
You just have to escape before the clock runs out.
要是逃不出来呢
Well, what happens if you don't?
会有人从那扇门进来
Some guy comes in through the door
告诉你错过了什么线索
and explains all the clues you missed.
让你感觉自己是个蠢蛋
He makes you feel like a total idiot.
游戏什么时候开始？
When does the game start?
我们要先等游戏大师过来
We are waiting for the Games Master
给我们讲解故事背景
to come in to give us the story
然后他再带我们去密室
and take us to the escape room.
比如  要是玩《僵尸启示录》
Like, it's a zombie apocalypse and we have to find
就得在被吃掉之前找到解药
the cure before we get eaten alive.
这个我喜欢  很有意思
I like that one. That one sounds good.
我估计这个游戏大师还在找停车位吧
While the Games Master is looking for a parking spot,
我先出去抽根烟
I'm going to go smoke a cigarette.
出口
烧烤  关
该死
Shit. Um...
门把手掉下来了
Hey, the doorknob came off.
你把门弄坏了吗？ 要不然呢
- What, you broke it? - Of course he did.
不是我弄坏的  是它自己掉的
I didn't break it, it broke.
你在自己家也这么开门吗？
Is that how you open a door in your house?
不是  -好了  你先别起急
- No. - Well, don't be so rough with it.
好吧  打扰一下  小姐
Well, excuse me, miss. Ma'am.
老天  这下精彩了
Oh, my God, this is awesome.
各位  我想这里就是我们要逃脱的密室
You guys, you guys, I think this is the escape room.
什么？
What?
等等  什么？
Wait, what?
好吧  这像是烤箱刻度盘  也就是说
Okay, it looks like an oven dial, which means
它可能是个密码锁
it's probably a combination lock.
好了  大家都来搜房间吧
All right, everyone search the room.
等一下  这就开始了吗？
Wait, wait. It's starting right now?
是的
- Yes. - Oh!
那找什么呢  兄弟？
What are we looking for here, bud?
找任何像是谜语或者密码的东西
Anything that looks like a puzzle or a code.
或者密码的东西  线索可能是任何东西  藏在任何地方
Numbers are very important. It could be anything, anywhere.
没准就在这底下
Maybe under here.
我得一直拿着这玩意吗  还是？
Do you want me to hold on to this or is it...?
拿着吧  这可是命根子
Yeah, just hold your knob there, guy.
行吧  你很幽默  对
Great. Very funny. Yeah.
我们知道你有路可走
烤肉月刊《焦痕》余无坦博士
米诺斯密室逃生  3楼
各位
Hey, guys.
各位  这些杂志都是
Hey, guys, these are all addressed
寄给同一个人的  他叫作余无坦博士
to the same guy, this Dr. Wootan Yu.
这应该是线索吧？
I mean, that's got to be a clue, right?
也许故事是这样的
Maybe that's the story.
可能他是个邪恶的科学家
Maybe he's like an evil scientist
我们必须逃出他的实验室
and we have to escape his lab
否则他就会把我们缝在一起
before he sews us all together
变成某种可怕的医学怪物
into some sort of medical abomination.
他的邪恶实验室还配了个等候室吗？
So, his evil lab has a waiting room?
《华氏451度》
他的邪恶实验室还配了个等候室吗？
So, his evil lab has a waiting room?
是啊  -别逗了
- Yeah. - No.
见鬼  真是见鬼
Shit. Shit, shit.
大家快看  我找到一把星型螺丝刀
Guys, look, look. I found a star-head screwdriver.
这肯定有用  对吧？
That's got to be something, right?
太好了  那要再找点螺丝钉吗？
Great. So, we're looking for screws?
不  这不是锤子
Well, this isn't a hammer.
这是螺丝刀  对吧？ -应该没错
- That's a star-head, right? - I think so. Yeah.
这是《华氏451度》
That's Fahrenheit 451.
好吧  她想到什么了
All right, she's got something.
怎么回事？ -不知道
- What was that? - I don't know.
怎么了吗？
Did that do anything?
好吧
Okay.
这下可厉害了  -是啊
- All right, now that's pretty cool. - Yeah.
有人带防晒霜了吗？
Anybody got suntan lotion?
你刚才做了什么？
What did you just do?
我以为书名是烤箱刻度盘的密码
I just thought the book was the code for the oven dial.
把它关掉  麻烦你
Turn it off, please.
这东西真的在升温
Wow, it's really throwing off some heat.
是  挺热的
Yeah, it's warm.
它在发热
It's kicking some heat.
这是什么  巨型加热线圈吗？
What are those, giant oven coils?
快关掉  -对不起  它卡住了
Turn it off. - I'm sorry. It's stuck.
我转不动
I can't move it.
该死  -这热度真要命
- Shit. - This is crazy hot.
你们能关掉吗？ -该死  好吧
Can you shut it off? - Shit. Okay.
别再碰什么了  好吗？
Don't touch anything else, okay?
你  游戏小子  就你
Hey, you, gamer boy, there.
我们该怎么办？ 怎么逃出去？
What do we do? How do we get out of here?
要是没头绪  可以要个提示
When you're stuck, you can ask for a hint.
要个提示？ 还能这么干吗？ 太好了  那走吧
A hint? That's an option? Okay, great. Here we go.
是  可我们自己想办法更有意思啊
Yeah, but it's way more fun if we do it ourselves.
说得好  游戏小子
Good one, gamer boy.
我也想靠自己
I kind of want to do it ourselves.
不好意思
Hi, excuse me.
我们现在想要提示  麻烦你  -对  你好
- We'd like our hint now, please. - Yeah, hello.
请您就座稍后会有人接待
Please have a seat. Someone will be with you shortly.
不是  不好意思  我们真的需要提示  拜托
No, yeah, excuse me, we'd really like our hint, please.
请您就座稍后会有人接待
Please have a seat. Someone will be with you shortly.
这话她之前就说过  -所以呢？
- She said that last time. - So?
她说得跟之前一模一样  节奏一样  语调也一样
She said it the exact same way. Same cadence, same tone.
他们总不会是雇了朱迪·丹奇爵士这样的演员吧
Well, the actors they hire aren't exactly Dame Judi Dench.
有人吗？ 我喜欢朱迪·丹奇
- Hello? Hello? - I love Judi Dench.
那颗雪花水晶球应该没什么用  老兄
Yeah, I don't think the snow globe's going to help, man.
各位  这里有个锁
Hey, guys, there's a lock over here.
棒  锁在密室逃生游戏里超级无敌关键
Yes. Locks are a super important part of escape rooms.
好吧
All right.
好吧  看来我们需要一把小钥匙
Okay, it looks like we need a small key
才能进到里面去
to get to the other side of the partition.
下一个线索可能就在里面
That's probably where the next clue is.
好吧  这我可帮不上忙了
Well, I'm not going to be any help there
因为我总是找不到钥匙
because I can never find my keys.
好笑  我们直接砸门算了
Hilarious. Or we could just break it off.
正好这里有个灭火器
There's an extinguisher right here.
好  好主意
Yeah, good idea.
不  我们不能使用暴力
No, no. We shouldn't have to use force.
这条游戏规则我之前忘记告诉你们了  我的错
That's actually the one rule I forgot to tell you. My bad.
干得好  -真棒
- Good one. - Great.
你还真是个破坏王啊
You're really good at breaking stuff, huh?
这个是塑料的
It's plastic.
又怎么了？
What was that?
是刚才那个声音  对吗？
That's that same sound, right?
兄弟  你刚才都干了什么
Man, what the hell did you just do?
该死
Oh, shit.
该死  这像是真的
Oh, shit, that looks real.
这只是为了吓唬我们
They're just trying to give us a scare
就是那个所谓的沉浸式体验
as part of the immersive experience.
搞什么  你是他们的托儿吗?
What the hell, are they paying you?
不是  我只是知道怎么才好玩
No, I just know how to have fun, I guess.
你觉得中暑好玩是吗?
Heat stroke is your idea of fun?
越来越热了
It's getting warm.
好了  也没那么糟  只要脱了外套就好
Hey, it's not that bad. Just take off your jacket.
谁还不知道要脱外套?
Hey, does anyone else have a problem with this?
各位  我想我找到钥匙了
Hey, guys, I think I've got the key.
等等  听着  小东西
Listen, short stuff...
在你冒冒失失
let's talk about this before you bring tiki torches
搞出大事之前我们先谈谈  好吗?
- out of the walls, okay?
别急  她找到钥匙了
- Hold on now. She's got a key.
就插进去试试呗
Why don't we stick it in the keyhole?
好  行  行  是我不好  试试吧
Okay, yeah. My bad. Let's try it.
来试试  快
Give it a shot, come on.
请您就座稍后会有人接待
Please have a seat. Someone will be with you shortly.
这个也太诡异了
Well, that's creepy as hell.
好  我去接  让开
Fine. Yeah. I'll get it. Move.
你好
Hello.
欢迎光临米诺斯
Welcome to Minos,
世界超一流的密室逃生设计公司
the world's preeminent designer of escape rooms.
为了您能顺利逃脱
To get the most out of your game,
建议您遵守所有已发布的规则
we recommend following all posted rules.
喂
Hey. Hey. Hello? Hello?
是谁？ 说什么了？
Who was it? What did they say?
是一段录音
It was a recording.
让我们遵守所有已发布的规则
It said to follow all the posted rules.
什么已发布的规则？
What posted rules?
该死
Oh, shit.
不  -是我干的吗？
No. - Did I do that?
不  到底是怎么回事？
No, no. What the literal hell?
拜托停下来  好了  我不玩了
Please stop. Okay, I'm done.
不  不  你这样大家都会紧张  懂吗？
No, no. You're stressing everyone out here, okay?
先去找点水喝  然后把外套脱了
Just go get some water and take off your damn jacket.
我们得想办法离开这个大烤箱
We've got to find a way out of this Easy-Bake Oven.
看着我  阿曼达
Okay, look at me, look at me. Amanda.
该死
Oh, shit.
那是风扇吗？ 它在吹热风吗？
Are those fans? Are they blowing hot air?
去找点水喝  知道吗？
We'll just get some water, okay?
你跟我去接水吧
Come and get some water with me.
我还好
I'm fine. Okay.
好吧  越来越热了
Yeah, it's getting hot,
不过也没发生什么
but nothing is going to happen to us.
烤箱都有风扇  -是啊  那又怎么样
Ovens have fans. - True, but so what?
去找已发布的规则吧
We've got to find the posted rules.
我才不管什么已发布的规则
I don't care about the posted rules.
窗边可能凉快一点
It might be colder by the windows.
我快烧着了
I'm burning up.
快点  想想怎么出去？
Come on, how do we get out of here?
你这么傻坐着能想出什么来
You're not going to solve anything by sitting on your ass.
我没傻坐着  我手扶着膝盖沉思呢
I'm not sitting on my ass. I'm on my hands and knees.
你们三个在干吗？ 快找线索  快
Hey, what are you three doing? Look for something, come on.
这么热  你还想让我干什么？
It's too hot. What do you want me to do?
姑娘们  快  水喝够了吧
Ladies, come on, enough with the water.
快来帮忙找线索
Get over here and help us look.
我们得先弄清楚线索是什么
We just have to figure out what the clue meant.
等等  这是什么？
Hold on. What's this?
哪有游戏会这么玩啊
There's no way this is part of the game.
线索都在哪里？
Where are all the clues at, huh?
大家快点  这里越来越热了
Guys, come on. It's getting hot in here.
我们总得想办法把这门打开
We've got to find something to break this door open.
老兄  我们不能使用暴力
Dude, we're not supposed to use force.
开门啊
Come on!
有完没完了？ 怎么才能出去？
When is this over? How do we get out?
越来越热了  我们会被活活烤死的
It's getting hotter. We're being baked alive.
各位  放松点
Guys, relax.
余无坦博士说任何时候都可以用杯垫
太变态了  谁设计的游戏？
This is sick. Who does this?
说点什么  本
Come on, Ben.
你们还想我怎么样？ 我什么也看不见啊
What do you want me to do? I can't see anything.
各位  我们得集中精神寻找线索
Guys, we need to focus and find the clues.
我感觉这里有六十多度
It's like 150 degrees in here.
（译者注：150华氏度≈65.56摄氏度）
佐伊  那幅画
Hey. Hey, Zoey, the painting.
我的天  那里有个出口
Oh, my God. There's an exit.
老天爷  快看那边
Oh, hot dog, look at that.
佐伊  再来一次  无论你干什么了  再来一次
Zoey, do that again. Whatever you did, just do it again.
各位  这是通风口  也许能出去
Hey, guys, it's a duct. It could be a way out.
大家看  这里还有很多杯垫
Guys, there are more coasters here.
快启动杯垫
Get on the coasters.
大家试着同时按下杯垫
Everyone try pressing down at the same time.
天啊  连桌子都是烫的
God, even the table's hot.
开了？ 我们是不是赢了？ -是的
- Is that it? Did we win the game? - Yeah.
我先出去  真棒  我们赢了
I'll go first. - All right, we win the game.
等等  我们手还按着呢
Wait, you're not going to just leave us
你不会自己跑路吧
with our dicks in our hands.
那有谁希望让这位替我探路？
Does anybody prefer this guy go instead of me?
我就知道没有  -是吗？
- That's what I thought. - Really?
这是通往哪里的？
Where does it go?
里面有多长？ -特别特别长
- How deep does it go?- It goes pretty far.
我的老天啊
Jesus Christ.
这太烫了
It's broiling.
这温度就没下来过
It's not getting any cooler in here.
我的天  我真期待下一个密室
Oh, my God. I'm so excited for the next room.
还有下一个密室吗？ -杰森？
- The next room? - Jason?
我好像找到出口了  不过有铁丝网挡着
Hey, I think I found a way out! It's blocked by a grate.
迈克  把那把螺丝刀给我  -好  在我口袋里
- Mike, bring that screwdriver. - Yeah! It's in my pocket.
有人能帮我拿出来吗  来  阿曼达
Someone get it out of my pocket for me. Come here, Amanda.
谁愿意把螺丝刀送过去？
Does anybody want to take the screwdriver?
我来按  你去  -真的吗？
- I've got it, I've got it. Go. - Are you sure?
对  快去
Yeah. Go, go.
让你去就去  你行的  迈克
- Just do it. - You've got this, Mike.
去啊  老兄  温度不会降下来的  动作快点  去
Go, man. It's not getting any colder. Hurry up, go.
迈克  你在哪里？ 我就来
Mike, where you at? - I'm coming.
你们就把这里看成互动式餐馆剧院吧
Hey, hey. Just think of it like interactive dinner theater.
我的老天  你说什么废话呢
Jesus Christ, you're not helping me here, man.
好吧  是  我火上浇油了  我错了
Okay, yeah. I'm making it worse. My bad.
你今天还能过来吗？
Are you going to come today or what?
小心别砸到脸  -你也小心别破相
- Watch your face down there. - You watch your face up there.
快点
Come on. Come on, come on.
我打开了  大家快过来
Hey, I got it. You guys, come on!
你想先走吗？ 阿曼达  应该你先走
Do you want to go? Amanda, you should go.
那好吧  你们按好这两个
Okay. Okay, here, take these.
好  那个他来  我按这个
Okay. He can take that. I'll hold it.
好  好了  去吧
- Okay. - All right, come on.
你可以的
You've got this.
好了
All right.
我感觉大家都在回避一个无法回避的问题
I feel like we're avoiding the inevitable conclusion here.
我们的手不够用了
We're running out of hands.
米诺斯
密室逃生
我有办法了  过来  你们把脚踩上来  拜托
I've got an idea. Come here. Put your foot on here, please.
好了
- Okay.
我就没玩过这么可怕的扭扭乐
This is the worst game of Twister ever.
动作能不能稍微快一点？
Can we move a little faster, please?
这招不行  -该死
- It didn't work. - Shit.
好吧  可能得把杯子装满
Okay, maybe it needs to be full.
我觉得我要晕过去了  -好了
- I think I'm going to pass out. - Okay.
快点
Come on, come on, come on. Come on!
把脚挪开  好了
You can move your foot. Okay.
成功了  好了
- It worked! - Yes, yes.
阿曼达？
Amanda?
要不你去帮帮她吧？
Hey, why don't you just go help her?
我们来装水
We'll fill the glasses.
别装正义骑士献殷勤了  老弟
Stop being chivalrous, dude.
这里没姑娘看得上你
No one here wants to have sex with you.
快去  -好
- Go! - Okay.
很好  非常好  本
Nice. Really nice, Ben.
该死
Shit.
加油  -好的
- Come on. - Okay.
她出去了  走走走  快
She's clear. Go, go, go. Come on.
快点  你个混蛋  求你了
Come on, you son of a bitch, please.
快快快
Come on, come on, come on.
阿曼达？ 阿曼达  我来了
Amanda? Amanda, I'm here.
好了  满了
Okay. Good.
怎么了？ 你能呼吸  你没被困住
What's wrong? You can breathe. You're not stuck.
跟我呼吸  一  二
Breathe in with me. One, two...
再来两杯
Two more.
这不是真的  这不是真的
This is not real. You're not stuck.
好  没事的  我在这里  好吗？ 我拉着你的手呢
You're okay. I'm here, okay? I'm holding your hand.
我保证哪里也不去  你没事的
I promise I'm right here. You're okay.
好了  再来一杯  再来一杯就行
Okay, we need one more. We just need one more.
该死  我们没水了
Shit, we're out of water.
那现在怎么办啊？
What are we supposed to do now?
我怎么知道？ 你才是逃脱专家
How would I know? You're the expert here.
马上就到了  马上就到了  我保证
We're really close. We're really close, I promise.
这都要怪你  知道吗
This is all your fault, you know.
什么？ -都怪你触发烤箱
- What? - You're the reason
阿曼达才会把线索都喝光
that Amanda drank all of our clues.
杰森就在那边  好吗？
Jason's right there, okay?
那时候我怎么知道这个饮水机
How was I supposed to know that the water cooler was...
不
Oh, no.
这下完蛋了  -怎么会这样？
- Well, that's not good. - What the fuck?
我的酒瓶
My flask. My flask.
你一直揣着这玩意吗？
You've had that the whole time?
我的天
Oh, my God.
快点  好了
Come on! Yes. Yes.
你想被烧死吗？ 快走
Do you want to burn to death? Let's go!
真见鬼
What the hell?
老天  这就是真实感啊
Oh, Jesus. Talk about immersive.
什么真实感？ 你是不是脑子坏掉了？ 这就是真的
Immersive? What the hell is wrong with you? That was real!
这只是一种干扰而已  -你在开玩笑吗  老弟？
- They're just messing with us. - Are you kidding me, dude?
听着  我出来之后才爆炸的
Look, it went off right as I cleared it.
懂吗  应该是我触发了什么机关
Okay, I must have triggered it.
游戏大师就是想让我们觉得像死里逃生
The Games Master wants us to think we barely made it.
不可能只有我觉得不对
I can't be the only one.
奖金有一万呢  我可不认输
Hey. It's ten grand and I don't lose.
我退出  行吗？
Well, I'm out, okay?
你们好  够了
Hi. Okay, I'm done.
我不玩了  你们立刻让我走
I want out. You let me out of here now!
我们现在是不是正在被监视？
You think they're watching us right now?
得了吧  塞尚锁具公司
- Come on. - "Sai-San lock and co."
好吧  还得再找一把钥匙
All right, so we need another key.
你手机给我  我要报警
Give me your phone. I'm calling the cops.
你先回想一下  好吗？
Think about it for a second, okay?
到现在为止我们出事了吗？
What has actually happened to us so far?
没有  你跟警察怎么说？
Nothing. What will you tell the cops?
怎么说  我就说我们被关进巨型烤箱
I don't know, maybe that they locked us
差点被人烤了吃
in a giant oven and tried to cook us.
这种游戏是经常有喷火环节吗？
Is open flame a common occurrence in these things?
不经常有  -原来不经常有
- Not really. - Not really.
把你手机给我
Give me your goddamn phone.
你真的有手机  你是怎么带进来的？
You do have a phone. How did you get a phone in here?
我偷带进来的
I snuck it in.
没有信号  -猜到了
- There's no signal. - Typical.
很正常  毕竟我们是在混凝土大楼里
Well, yeah. We're in a giant concrete building.
各位  我们能逃出去的  你们看看这里
Guys, we can figure this out. I mean, look at this place.
我想说  这里再来杯热巧克力就是度假小屋啊
I mean, the only thing missing is the hot chocolate.
好吧  那你说这游戏得玩多久？
All right, how long do you think this game is going to last?
我也不知道  我有一次玩过有五个密室的
I mean, I don't know. I did one that had, like, five rooms once.
五个吗？
Five?
五个密室这么多？ 好吧
Five rooms? Okay.
好吧  所以刚才那种事还得再来四次
Okay. So, that means we just need to do that four more times.
开个玩笑  好了各位  我们能行
I'm kidding. Come on, guys, we can do this.
刚才那是目前最难的
That was the hardest roomby far, right?
最难的都放第一关  对吗  丹尼？
They front-loaded it, right, Danny?
对  毕竟对他们来说每个密室
Yeah. I mean, I'm sure they can't afford
都烧一次也太费钱了
to light every room on fire.
就是嘛  看看这里
Exactly. Look at it.
都是木头  一点就着啊
This place is a goddamn tinder box.
这里有第二把锁  各位
Hey. Hey, second lock, guys.
密码是一个七个字母的单词
It looks like we need a seven-letter word.
要不我们分头行动  去找线索吧
Let's spread out and see what we can find.
好的
Okay.
你一定会被载入史册
"You'll go down in history."
这有什么含义吗？
What about this? Could that mean something?
你一定会被载入史册
"You'll go down in history."
You'll go down in history. You'll go down in history.
会是某个总统的名字吗？ 也许是总统姓氏
Maybe a president's name? Maybe a president's last name.
哪个总统的姓氏有七个字母？
What presidents have a seven-letter last name?
麦迪逊  杰克逊  林肯  约翰逊  哈丁
Madison, Jackson. Lincoln, Johnson, Harding.
慢点说  小雨人  -你太没礼貌了
- Whoa. Slow down there, Rain Man. - That's offensive.
第一个是什么？ 麦迪逊
What was the first one? Madison.
M-A-D-I-
-S-O-N.
不对  没有反应  还有什么来着？
No, that didn't work. What was another one?
约翰逊  -约翰逊吗  好  约翰逊
- Johnson. - Johnson. Okay, Johnson.
J-O-H-N-S-O-N.
不对  还有呢？
No, what else?
对了  杰克逊
Yeah, Jackson.
J-A-C-K-S-O-N.
下一个是什么来着？
What's the next name?
试试林肯  林肯  -林肯吗？
Try Lincoln. Lincoln. - Lincoln?
L-I-N-C-O-L-N.
这边有字母  但是有九个
There are letters here, but there are nine.
不行  还是打不开
No, that doesn't work either.
♪ 驯鹿们都很喜欢他 ♪
♪ How the reindeer Loved him ♪
♪ 它们一起快乐地大叫 ♪
♪ As they shouted out With glee ♪
♪ 鲁道夫红鼻子驯鹿 ♪
♪ Rudolph The red-nosed reindeer ♪
♪ 你一定会被载入史册 ♪
♪ You'll go down in history ♪
戴什  当瑟  普兰瑟  维克森
Dasher, Dancer, Prancer, Vixen...
科密  丘比特  唐纳  布利岑
Comet, Cupid, Donner, Blitzen.
你一定会被载入史册  -他在念叨什么呢？
- You'll go down in history. - What is he talking about?
密码是鲁道夫  -他说鲁道夫吗？
- It's "Rudolph." - Did he say "Rudolph"?
对  试试鲁道夫  -好  那就试试鲁道夫
- Yeah, try "Rudolph." - All right, "Rudolph" it is.
对了
Bingo!
快看看  没想到他挺行啊
Look at that. Hey, he helps.
是的
All right.
你们看  接下来一定会很好玩
Hey, see? It's going to be fine from now on.
不会再那么吓人了
No more scary shit.
你还好吗？
are you okay?
我还好  没事
Yeah, fine.
看看  一会儿热一会儿冷的
Look at this, going from hot to cold.
这样最容易生病
You know, that's how you get sick.
我有个傻问题  这真是户外吗？
Dumb question.Are we outside...
还是我出现幻觉了？
or am I stone-cold tripping?
我也搞不清楚  老兄  这里太冷了
I don't know, man. This place is really cold.
（译者注：30华氏度≈-1.1摄氏度）
现在是零下一度  还在降温
It's 30 degrees and dropping.
这游戏真好玩  是吧？
Real fun game, huh?
有人吗
Echo!
这地方简直太荒唐了
This whole place is bullshit.
我们得快点找到出口
The sooner we figure this out,
才能早点离开这里
the sooner we get the hell of out here.
这里太美了  天啊
This is beautiful. Oh, man,
我倒想在这儿多待一会儿
I could hang out in here for a while.
这里像个滑冰场
It's like ice skating.
滑向广阔的天地吧  丹尼  -小心点
- Into the great wide open, Danny! - Be careful.
去吧  老弟  探探路
Keep going, man. Check it out.
你要去哪里？ -让他去看看
Yeah, where are you going? - Let him figure it out.
各位？ -大家都别动
Guys? - Hey, nobody move.
行了  各位  放松点  好吗？ 没事的  看
Come on, guys. Relax, okay? It's fine. Look.
别这么干
Hey, don't do that.
刚才只是音效
It's just a sound effect.
冰面没有裂开
The ice isn't cracking.
他们正看着呢
They are watching to make sure
不会让我们出什么意外的
nothing bad happens to us.
要是真有人受伤
I mean, can you imagine the lawsuits
知道他们会吃多少官司吗？
if one of us actually got hurt?
得学会笑对人生啊各位  真是
Learn to have some fun in your life. Jeez.
这设计者简直是艺术家
Whoever did this is an artist.
怎么回事？
What is that?
丹尼  快回来  -回这边来  快  丹尼
- Danny, come on back. - Get over here. Hurry up, Danny.
该死
Shit.
通风口正在喷冷风
There's freezing air coming through those vents.
快点  丹尼
Come on, Danny!
丹尼  快点回来
Danny, get back here.
我回来了
Okay. I'm coming. I'm coming.
见鬼  真的太冷了  -我们靠在一起能暖和点
- Shit, that is cold. - Get together for body heat.
这风冷死我了  -挨紧点
- Oh, the air is freezing. - Stay close.
这真是厉害了  -他们干吗要这么玩？
- This is awesome. - Why are they doing this?
快  再挨紧点  -老天  太冷了
Come on, get closer. - Oh, my God, that's cold.
我们该去找找线索
We should look for clues.
有人吗？
Hello?
开门
Open, open, open.
要不你也看看？ -好
- Yeah, do you want to look? - Yeah.
没有真正的北方
"True north is a lie."
你在看什么呢？
What are you looking at?
乖狗狗
Good boy.
我发现一扇门  得找把小钥匙
Hey, I found a door. We need a small key.
这外套哪里来的？
Where did that come from?
六个人  就找到这一件？
One coat for six people?
看出他们打什么主意了吧？
You know what they're trying to do, right?
他们要我们互相争抢有限的资源  我的天啊
They want us to fight over limited resources. Jesus Christ.
臭混蛋们
Hey. Hey, assholes.
这次你们别想得逞  懂吗？
It's not going to work this time, okay?
我们会轮着穿
We're going to share it.
佐伊  你先穿
Zoey, you go first.
谢谢
Thank you.
该死  水怎么这么冷  -本
Shit, that's cold. - Ben.
该死  冻死我了
Shit! Oh, that's cold.
虚惊一场  大家别怕
Hey, false alarm, everybody.
这垂钓用的洞这么大  你没看见吗？
A giant fishing hole. How did you miss that?
这个洞有什么用呢？
What are we supposed to do with this?
水底下可能有线索
There could be a clue at the bottom.
是吗？ 那你怎么不潜下去找找？
Oh, really? Why don't you go dive in and check?
好吧  虽然我觉得这游戏世界第一好玩
Okay, it just feels like I'm playing
但队友也是世界第一嘴贱
the world's funnest game with the world's meanest people.
该死  我的腿都冻麻了
I can't feel my goddamn leg.
各位  -迈克？
- Hey, guys. - Mike?
看  我找到了
Look, I've got it.
我找到线索了
I mean, I've got something.
刚刚大概是
I just climbed a tree for, like,
我这辈子第一次爬树
the first time in my goddamn life.
丹尼  这东西应该有用吧
Danny, tell me this is something we can use.
有用  绝对是线索
Yeah, totally. It's a clue.
总算啊  该我表现表现了
Finally, something I'm good at.
你是要表现怎么拿着棍子站在洞口吗？
You mean you can stand over a hole and hold a stick?
有你在真给力
Wow, thank God you're here.
我知道你现在很冷
I understand you're cold right now,
可你要是再敢
but if you say something disrespectful to me
对我说这种不尊敬的话  我就替你父母履行
like that again... I'm going to give you
未尽的管教义务了
the slap your parents should have years ago.
是吗？ -回得真漂亮
Oh, really? - That's amazing.
我乐意效劳
With pleasure.
那我们现在怎么办
So, what are we supposed to do now,
难道就站在这里等线索上钩吗？
just stand here and wait to catch a clue?
这水可能非常深
Well, it's probably really deep.
（译者注：20英尺=6.096米）
是  钓鱼线已经放下六米了
Yeah, I'm about 20 feet down already.
什么都看不见
I can't even see.
这就是浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
你觉得是浪费时间吗？
You think this is a waste of time?
对  -真是要冻死人了
Yeah. - It's so goddamn cold.
我觉得这就是干扰设置
I do. I think it's a distraction.
这整套游戏都是浪费时间
I think this whole thing is a waste of time.
这根钓鱼竿可是我费了老大劲儿
I climbed up to the top of that tree.
爬到树顶上才发现的
I found a fishing rod up there.
真正的北方
True north.
什么？
What?
你到底想告诉我什么呢？
What are you trying to tell me?
没有真正的北方
True north is a lie.
他们可能正一边看着我们  像傻子一样围在洞口
They're probably watching us, laughing their asses off,
以便使劲儿嘲笑我们呢
as we stand around a hole like a bunch of morons.
可能再等等就有了  -去你的吧
- We probably just have to wait. - Oh, screw that, man.
这个给我  迈克  给我  迈克  快给我
Give me this, Mike. Mike, give me the pole!
你能不能冷静点？
Why don't you chill out, man?
你根本就不会钓鱼
You don't know what you're doing, man.
缠线架都没打开
You don't even have the release open.
不要放线
Don't let it out.
你得让钓线垂到水底
You've got to drop it to the bottom.
见鬼  这么深
Shit, that's deep.
不管了  给  你拿吧
Screw this. Here, take this.
把它还给我
Give me that back.
对不起  我只是
I'm sorry, all right? I just
太冷了  我快被冻疯了
I hate the cold and it makes me go crazy.
以前冬天我都在夏威夷过
I have to spend every winter in Kauai.
真巧啊  我还去法国南部过冬呢
Me, too. When I'm not in the South of France.
佐伊穿着外套去哪里了？
Hey, where's Zoey with that jacket?
我得穿会儿外套
I need that jacket.
就是它
Yes.
你能别在我旁边抽烟吗？
Hey, you mind not smoking that around me?
收线  我找到线索了
Pull up the line. I found something.
快把线拉上来  -什么？
- Pull up the line. - What?
各位  我找到线索了
Everyone, I found something.
你找到什么了
What do you got there?
又一条线索？ 厉害啊  佐伊
Another clue? Impressive, Zoey.
是什么？ -来吧
- What is it? - Okay.
是磁铁  原来如此  -别急
- A magnet, of course. - I'm with you. Okay, okay.
好了  快试试
Okay, try it. Try it now.
往后退
All right, all right. Stand back.
下去了
There she goes.
佐伊  外套该换人穿了
Zoey, your turn is up.
对  抱歉
Right. Sorry.
该死  好吧  它已经到底了
Oh, shit. Okay. I'm on the bottom.
不  有了
No, I'm hooked.
好的  有东西
All right, I've got something.
它吸上了
I've got something here.
没错  绝对吸上了
Yeah, I'm definitely hooked.
天啊
Oh, God.
真棒  -天啊  真重
- Nice. - God, that's heavy.
可以  我抓到了
Okay. Okay, I've got it. I've got it.
你抓到了吗？
You've got it?
好像是一把钥匙
We've got a key or something.
上来了  好吧
You've got it. Okay.
这一定是那扇门的钥匙
That's got to be the key to the door.
谁想的破游戏？ 一  二  三
- Who thinks of this shit? - One, two, three.
再来  一  二  三
Okay. One, two, three.
好吧  -该死  太结实了
- Okay. - Shit, that is solid.
本  打火机借一下  -对  这主意好
- Hey, Ben. We need your lighter. - Oh, yeah, that's a good idea.
借给你  我有什么好处？
What do I get in return?
你爱听单向乐队的唱片  以后我不跟你抢了
I won't take any of your One Direction CDs.
快拿来吧  老弟
Come on, just give it, man.
要打火机是吧？
All right, you want the lighter?
给
Here.
拿去吧
There you go.
算了  我去捡  -谢了  丹尼
- Okay, I'll get it. - Thanks, Danny.
钥匙冻在冰块正中间是吧？
Man, that is buried right in the center, isn't it?
顺便一提  不用谢
Oh, and you're welcome, by the way.
还真是多谢
Thanks a lot.
丹尼？
Danny?
怎么回事？ 怎么了？ 丹尼人呢？
What was that? What happened? Where's Danny?
你说话啊  他人呢？
Say something. Where is he?
他掉下去了
He just fell through.
他怎么会掉下去？
What do you mean, he fell through?
他在冰层下面
He's under the ice!
丹尼
Danny! Danny! Danny!
别慌  我下去救他
All right, I'm going in after him.
不行  冰层下面有暗流
No, no. There is a current under there.
你就算找到他
Even if you find him,
也不可能带他游回洞口
you will not make it back to the hole.
丹尼  你在哪里？
Danny, where are you?
他被水流卷到别处去了
He's being dragged around under there.
丹尼
Danny!
丹尼  你在哪里？
Danny, where are you?
丹尼  他去哪里了？ -谁看见他了？
- MIKE: Danny! Where did he go? - Do you see him?
我找不到他  -丹尼
- I can't see him. - Danny!
别吵
Shush, shush, shush! Shush!
天啊  丹尼  -他在哪里？
Oh, my God. Danny. - Where is he?
丹尼
Danny. Danny, Danny.
发生了什么？
What happened?
你说得对
You were right.
这游戏是真的
This is real.
怎么会这样？
How did it happen?
怎么会这样？ -什么？
- How did it happen? - What?
丹尼是怎么掉进去的？ 只有你看见了
How did Danny fall in? You're the only one who saw.
他就站在那里  然后冰面破了  他就掉下去了
He was there and then it exploded and then he fell.
是你把打火机扔给他的  你怎么就一点事都没有？
You threw him the lighter and somehow you're perfectly fine?
我扔到冰面那头去了  这样确实很过分
I threw it across the ice. I was just being an asshole.
你是正好扔到那里然后冰面正好就破了吗？
Yeah, you threw it to the exact spot that just happened to collapse?
你以为是我故意害他吗？
Are you saying that I did it?
这是你说的  我可没说
Yeah, hey, your words, not mine.
丹尼之前一直说什么游戏大师
Danny kept talking about a Games Master.
是啊  没准他就在我们中间
Yeah. Well, maybe he's already here.
什么游戏大师？ 我就是在杂货店里打杂的  好吗？
Games Master? I work at a grocery store, all right?
杰森才是我们当中
I mean, Jason's the one here
最像变态杀人狂的人
with the whole American Psycho vibe.
迈克  你就像躲在卡车休息站的怪胎
Mike, you're like the creep at the truck stop.
佐伊  真的对不起
And Zoey, I'm really sorry,
但我觉得你是那种会被父母锁在地下室
but it seems like your parents locked you in a basement
不写完作业不准出来的孩子
until you finished all your homework.
还有她  再看看她
And her. What about her?
她那些伤疤都是哪里来的？
I mean, where did she get all the scars?
来自伊拉克战争  混蛋
I served in Iraq, asshole.
所以你在军队待过？
Oh, so you've had military experience?
所以你才会这么像
So, that makes you like a...
疯子女战士
psycho Xena.
我只是想说  跟你们比  我才是最正常的
I'm just saying here, I'm, like, the least suspicious one.
这事就不是我的  够了  闭嘴
Okay, you know what? Shut up!
这些都是废话  懂吗？
None of it matters, all right?
不管幕后黑手是谁  要是不想冻死在这里
Whoever did this to us will let us freeze to death,
我们就得把钥匙从冰块里取出来
if we don't get the key out of that ice.
好吧  既然本的打火机不见了
Okay. Since Ben's lighter is gone,
那我们就围住冰块尽量用体温融化它
we have to surround it with as much body heat as possible.
你只关心本的打火机不见了吗？
Ben's lighter is gone?
丹尼刚刚死了
Danny is dead.
你知道如果体温过低会怎么样吗？
Do you know what happens when you get hypothermia?
你会失去方向感  还有判断力
You get disoriented and confused.
我不在乎你有多聪明
And I don't care how smart you are
又或者读过多少书
or how many books you read,
反正你会忘掉你是怎么来的
you won't remember how you got here,
也不会知道该怎么逃出去
much less how to get out.
都给我到这边来
You guys get over here
把双手放到冰块上
and put your hands on this ice.
我知道很冷  但冰块在融化了
I know it's cold, but it's melting, guys.
加油  继续捂着就好
Come on, just keep your hands on it.
外套给你
Hey, jacket.
我来托一会儿吧  真够冷的
Let me take it for a minute. Oh, that's cold.
好  给你
Okay. Here.
你怎么样  迈克？
How are you doing there, Mike?
你懂的  -要休息会儿吗？
- Oh, you know. - Need a break?
不用  没事  我能行
Mm-mm. No, I got it.
我能行  谢谢
I'm okay. I'm okay. Thank you.
我就是想不通
I just can't figure it out.
这游戏是谁设计的？
Who would do this?
一个心思缜密  无所不知的人
Someone who thought of every detail.
迈克？ -迈克
- Mike? - Hey, Mike.
背靠着树
Hey, put your back against the tree.
没事的  我们在呢  知道吗？
No, I'm okay. - We're here, okay?
我们都在呢
Hey, we're here, we're here.
杰森？ -他要去哪里？
- Jason? - Where's he going?
他把钥匙拿走了  大家快起来
He's got the key. You guys, come on.
快起来  好
- Get up, come on. - Okay.
门在哪里？ -杰森
- Where is it at? - Hey, Jason.
门在哪里？
Where's it at? Where's the door?
杰森  -放开我
- Jason! - Get off me!
门在哪里？
Where's the door?
那里有门吗？
There's a door?
快打开
Open it.
快把门打开
Open the goddamn door! Open up!
把门打开  把这该死的门打开
Open this door! Open the goddamn door!
你把门打开了
Hey, you did it, you opened a door.
快走  -杰森  我们走
- Move. - Jason! Let's go!
等等
Wait.
该死
Oh, shit!
等一下  佐伊  快点
Wait, wait. - Zoey, come on!
你们等等我
Wait for me!
本
Ben!
大家都还好吗？
Hey, is everyone okay?
我的手脚都冻僵了
I can't feel my extremities.
8号球
生啤
我的手脚都冻僵了
I can't feel my extremities.
那是什么？
What is that?
8号球
生啤
那是什么？
What is that?
8号球
台球室
当然了
Sure, why not?
好吧
Well...
往好的方面看  至少这地方很暖和
glass half full, at least it's warm in here.
天啊
Oh, my God.
这是怎么了？
What's happening? What is that?
我们在移动吗？ -对  抓稳
- Are we moving? - Yeah. Hold on.
我们在上升吗？ -对
- What, are we going up? - Yeah.
米诺斯大厦有几层？
How many floors is this building?
十五到二十层吧
15 to 20 floors.
我想应该不是送我们上来看风景的
Well, I'm guessing they didn't shoot us up here for the view.
好吧
Okay.
我们怎么上去接电话？
How are we supposed to answer that?
你好？
Hello?
真是一群混蛋
- Son of a bitch!
天啊  太刺耳了  疼死我了
God, that's loud. And it sucks.
真棒  我们会在电梯音乐声中死去
Oh, great, we're going to die to elevator music.
各位  上面这扇门没有把手
Guys, hey, this door up here doesn't have a handle.
看来得找个门把手
I think we're looking for a doorknob.
我们四处找找吧
Let's see what we can find.
♪ Listen to the music
Of the traffic in the city ♪
♪ Linger on the sidewalk
The neon signs are pretty ♪
余无坦博士
♪ Linger on the sidewalk
The neon signs are pretty ♪
♪ How can you lose
The lights are much... ♪
八号球  台球桌上没有八号球
Hey, the eight ball, it's missing from the pool table.
你们看  我去看看球杆架
Look at that. I'm going to check these cue racks.
没准能找到什么有用的
Maybe there's something over here we can use.
迈克  停下  -迈克
- Hey. Mike, stop! - Mike! Mike!
快离开那里  找个东西抓住
Get away from the edge. Grab onto something.
我的老天  -迈克  退后
- Oh, Jesus Christ. - Mike, step back! Mike!
你们快回来  -别站在地板上
Guys, come on. - Hey, get off the floor!
迈克  快点  迈克  别站在地板上
Mike, hurry up! Mike, get off the floor.
该死  -你们看见了吗？
- Shit. - Did you see that?
这又是搞什么鬼？
What the hell's going on?
这到底是什么机关  抢椅子游戏吗？
What is this, like, musical chairs?
我们怎么办？
What do we do now?
还能怎么办  想办法活下去
I don't know, try not to die.
阿曼达  你要想清楚
Hey, Amanda, just think about this.
让我试一下
Just let me try this.
快快快
Go, go, go.
该死  -你还好吗？
- Oh, shit. - Are you okay?
还好  只是出汗了  该死
Yeah, it's just wet. Oh, shit.
好了  我继续
Okay, here I go.
试试关一下收音机？ 可能音乐就停了
Hey, what about the radio? Maybe it'll shut the music off.
不行  音乐不是这里传出来的
No, I don't think it's connected.
再看看上面那几台制冷机？
What about those coolers at the top?
好
Okay.
没准能找到门把手
Maybe the handle's in there.
别忘了顺便找找八号球
And keep your eyes peeled for that eight ball.
好的
Okay.
这个密室里面的摆设简直是太诡异了
Yeah, the craftsmanship in here is just terrifying.
我很不喜欢这个密室
I hate this room so much.
各位  这里有个保险箱
Guys, I've got a lock box.
好了
All right.
需要一个四位密码
It looks like I need four numbers.
好吧  试试一二三四  瞎猜一个
All right, try one-two-three-four. Just to see.
看来这是迈克的惯用密码
I guess we know Mike's PIN code.
不对
Nope.
好吧  再试试四个一
All right. Try one-one-one-one.
我们从最简单的来吧
You know, go back to the basics.
什么？ 四个一吗？
What? One-one-one-one?
不对  还是打不开
Uh, nope. That's not it.
那是个巨型的滑块拼图
It's a giant sliding puzzle.
佐伊  -佐伊
- Zo? - Zoey?
佐伊  你要干什么？-佐伊
- Zoey, what are you doing? - Zo?
小心点
Careful. Careful, careful, careful.
干得好  佐伊
Good job, Zo.
可以了  佐伊  站在那里就行
That's good, Zoey. Just stay there.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
不能一直扒在这个书架上
I can't hang around on this bookshelf all day.
我不该动的  天啊
This was a bad idea. Oh, God.
好吧  一  二  三
Come on. One, two, three.
上去吧
Up you get.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了
Okay.
该死
Oh, shit!
我的天  真是见鬼
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, shit.
杰森  抓紧
Jason, hold on!
我没事  老天  我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay. Oh, God. I'm okay. Oh, God.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
继续吧  我没事
Keep going. Keep going. I'm okay.
没关系  好的
He's okay. It's okay, he's okay.
你一定能行
You've got this. You've got this.
能不能想个办法把这破音乐给关了？
Is there anything we can do about this shitty music?
天啊
Oh, God!
我的老天爷啊
Oh, my God.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
我拼好了
Hey, I've got it.
什么？
What?
我拼好了
Got it.
那里有好多颜色  我看见黄色
There are colors. I see yellow...
黑色和蓝色
black, and blue.
对对对  还有上下两道杠  中间夹个圆  杠和圆
Yeah, yeah, yeah, and we've got two lines and a circle.
像摩斯密码  也许是摩斯密码
It's like Morse code. Maybe it's Morse code.
两道杠夹个圆是台球的样子
Stripes and circles. They're billiard balls.
带杠的黄色球是九号球
The yellow stripe, that's a nine.
九  下一个数字
Nine. Next.
那个黑圆圈明显是八号球  八号球
The black ball, like, that's the eight ball, obviously.
八  还有两位  -带杠的蓝色球 是十号球
- Eight. Two more. - Blue stripe, that's ten.
试试一和零
Try one-zero.
一  零  真见鬼了
- One-zero. Goddamn it.
该死
- Shit!
快快快  别踩地板
Go, go, go. - Get off the floor.
迈克  你行的  快上来
You've got it, Mike. Come on.
天啊
Oh, my God.
坚持住  好吗？
Hold on, okay?
那架子支撑不了你们三个人
That thing's not going to hold all three of you.
迈克  你先下去  -下哪里去？
- Mike, climb off. - And go where?
你右边还有个架子  -在那里
- Use that rack on your right. - Here, here.
各位   都坚持住  好吗？
Guys, just hang on, okay?
该死  我不行
Oh, shit, I can't. I can't.
迈克  看着我  你必须从那个书架上下去
Mike, look at me. Get off the goddamn shelf
不然大家都得送命
before you get everybody killed.
迈克  男人点儿
Mike, man up.
你别冲他吼了  行吗？ 别说了
Stop yelling at him, okay? Stop.
迈克  我下去  我能下去  好吗？ 你待着
Mike, I'll move. I can move, okay? Just stay there.
待着别动
Just stay there. Don't worry about it.
快
Just go, go.
佐伊  把手给我
Zoey. Hey, give me your hand.
快  把手给我
Come on,give me your hand.
佐伊  快点  -小心点
Zoey, hey. Come on. - Careful.
快把手给我  佐伊
Come on, give me your hand. Zoey. Zoey!
佐伊  佐伊
Zoey. Hey, Zoey.
天啊
Oh, God!
真该死  -佐伊
Goddamn it! - Zoey!
你得站起来  快
You've got to get up. Come on.
佐伊  醒醒  佐伊  从地上起来
Zoey, wake up. Zoey, get off the floor.
佐伊  回答我  各位  你们撑住  我去救她
Zoey, stay with me. Hey, you guys come on, I'll go get her.
请回答  越南航空109号航班
Come in, Vietnam Air 109.
妈妈
Mom. Mom. Mom.
Mama. Mom!
佐伊  快醒醒
Zoey, come on, wake up.
佐伊  醒醒  快醒醒
Zoey, wake up. Zoey, come on.
得赶紧起来  佐伊  快点
We've got to go. Zoey, come on!
我们颠倒了
We're upside down.
快点
Hey. Come on, come on.
上去
Hey, go, go.
这密室上下颠倒  所以密码要倒过来
The room is upside down, so the code might be, too.
对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
这次试试零一八六
Try zero-one-eight-six.
零  一  八  六
Zero-one-eight-six.
打开了  -打开了  快走
- I've got it.- Okay, we've got it. Come on.
佐伊你真是天才  -走啊  动作快
Zoey, you're a genius. - Come on, hurry up.
快点  本  快过去
Come on, Ben, hurry up. Hurry up.
快走  快走  -好了
- Come on. Hurry up. - Okay.
快点  地板要塌了
Come on, the floor's going to drop.
这个破地板差点又要了我的命
That is the second time this floor has tried to kill me.
该死
Shit.
加油  杰森
Come on, Jason.
我上来了
I've got it.
好了
Okay.
好吧
来吧  -阿曼达  你要小心
- Okay. - Amanda, be careful.
挺住
Hang on. Hang on.
快点  你可以的
All right, you've got this.
对
Yes. Yes.
好了  -不  别往下看
- All right. - No, don't look down.
好的
Okay.
你能行
You've got it.
好吧
Okay.
加油
Come on. Come on.
好的  -该死  不
- Okay. - Shit. Oh, no.
球  -不
The ball! - No!
别管球了
Just let it go!
别管球了  别下去
Just leave it. - Hey, stop, stop!
别管球了  -阿曼达
- Just leave it. - Amanda!
不
- No!
该死
Oh, shit!
杰森
Jason!
我接住了  -快跳开
- I got it. The cord! - Jump!
把台球杆给我
Hey, give me the pool cue.
对  好主意  撑住
Yeah, good idea. Hang on.
撑住  阿曼达  快  伸过去
Hang on, Amanda. Hang on. Come on, reach out there.
抓住它  快点  抓住
- Grab on to this, come on! -  Grab it.
没法再远了
I can't get it any farther.
你可以的
Hey, you can do it.
阿曼达  你可以的
You can do it, Amanda.
抓住就行  好吗？
You can do this. Just grab it, okay?
快抓住它
Grab on to it!
加油  你可以的  它就在你眼前
Come on, you got this. It's just right there.
阿曼达  听我说  你可以的
Amanda, listen to me. You can do it.
你可以的  我们都在这里  好吗？挺住
You can do this. We're right here. Okay? Stay.
算了吧
It's okay.
阿曼达  不  挺住  好吗？ 坚持一下  算了吧
Amanda! No, stay, okay? Just hold on, just hold on. No!
不
No!
不不不
- No, no, no! No, no!
不  阿曼达  不要
No, Amanda, no, no!
佐伊  快走  走啊  出来
Zoey, come on. Hey, come on. Get out!
不
No.
分诊室
这又是什么鬼密室？
What in the hell is this supposed to be?
我没看见出口  你们发现什么了吗？
I don't see a way out. Do you see anything?
小神童  帮我想想  到里面来
Hey, wunderkind, I need your brain. Get in here.
佐伊
Zoey!
你就不能让她缓缓吗？ 阿曼达刚刚才死
Will you give her a minute? Amanda just died!
你们这些人怎么就搞不明白？
What don't you people understand?
我们不能再浪费时间了
We don't have minutes to waste.
阿曼达是死了  我们还活着
Amanda is dead. We aren't.
弱肉强食  适者生存
Survival of the fittest.
你怎么这么混蛋？
Will you stop being a dick?
你就不能有点良心吗？
What is your problem?
阿曼达一点也不弱  好吗？ 她是为了我们才牺牲的
Amanda wasn't weak, okay? She sacrificed herself for us!
对  那我们就更不该轻易送死
Okay, well, then let's not waste that sacrifice
否则她就是白白牺牲了
by getting yourself killed.
迈克·诺兰
气胸
这是我以前的病房
This was my room.
越南丘当医院  个人信息
名字  佐伊  姓氏  戴维斯
简直是一模一样
Exactly the same.
这是我以前的病床
This is my bed.
我的也有
Me, too.
圣弗朗西斯青年医院
低体温症
病人  杰森·沃克先生
沃克先生是唯一的幸存者
这是阿曼达的
It's Amanda's.
事故报告  烧伤患者
患者姓名  阿曼达·哈珀中尉
事故描述  土制炸弹爆炸
土制炸弹爆炸
IED blast.
她是唯一的幸存者
She was the only survivor.
我曾经和妈妈坐飞机
I was on a plane with my mom...
当背包客  穿越整个越南
backpacking across Vietnam.
飞机坠毁在了一片丛林里
The plane just crashed in the middle of the jungle.
我过了一周才获救
It took them a week to find me.
我有印象
I remember that.
你上过新闻
You were on the news.
我和大学室友一起划船出海
My college roommate and I took a boat out...
突然一个大浪打过来
and a wave came out of nowhere and just...
直接掀翻了整艘船
flipped the boat over.
我想抓住船上的绳子
And I tried to grab a line and, uh...
拇指都差点勒断
almost took my thumb off.
我们湿透了
Wet...
冷得要命  只能拼命扒着船身
freezing, just holding on to the hull...
当时我们两个人只有一件外套
with only one jacket between the two of us.
我室友南森  他突然变得非常暴力而且神志不清
And Nathan, he started getting aggressive and confused.
就是体温过低的症状
It was signs of hypothermia,
这是我后来去医院才知道的
they told me later in the hospital.
南森  快回来
Nathan, come back!
到了第二天  他游走了
On the second day, he swam off.
我不知道他出现了什么幻觉
I don't know what he thought he saw out there...
反正海面上什么都没有
but there was nothing but ocean.
第三天  海岸警卫队只找到了我
The next day, the Coast Guard found me alone.
你呢？
What about you?
我是朋友中第一个有车的
I was the first of my friends to get a car.
放寒假的时候  我和朋友们
It was winter break and we were having this...
开心地玩到深夜
great night and...
我想开车带大家出去兜兜风
I wanted to take everybody out on a joy ride.
可是我喝醉了
I was wasted.
我曾和十一个伙伴在西弗吉尼亚州当矿工
Me and 11 others were working a mine in West Virginia...
其中包括我弟弟卡尔
including my little brother, Cal.
矿井塌了  这行就是危险
There was a cave-in. Occupational hazard.
当时我和卡尔正好一起被困在矿井里
Me and Cal got pinned right next to each other.
我看不见他  但我能
I couldn't see him, but I could, uh...
我能听见他渐渐窒息的声音
I could hear him suffocating slowly.
我听着他咽下最后一口气
I heard him take his last breath.
等救援队赶到的时候
By the time the rescue crew got there,
只剩下我一个人还活着
I was the only one alive.
游戏的设计者对我们的事了如指掌
They knew everything about us...
每个细节都一清二楚  他们还知道那件外套
every goddamn detail. I mean, they knew the jacket...
我和室友当时在船上穿的那件外套
that my roommate was wearing on that boat.
还有鲁道夫红鼻子驯鹿  那是
"Rudolph the Red-Nosed  Reindeer," that's the...
我们出车祸时放的歌
song that was playing when we crashed.
这些密室是为我们定制的
They made these rooms for us.
盒子上写的寄件人都是我们信任的人
They addressed the boxes from people that we trust.
我侄子给我发短信说  祝你玩得开心
My nephew texted me, "Have a good time."
这帮混蛋黑进了他的手机  -这是丹尼的
- They hacked his goddamn phone. - It's Danny's.
一氧化碳中毒
Carbon monoxide poisoning.
血检结果
一氧化碳中毒
他们家除了他都死了
Everyone in his family was killed but him.
我们全都没死  对吗？
None of us died, right?
我们都是唯一的幸存者  -所以呢？
- We're sole survivors. - So what?
我们从概率上来说就不该活下来
We're a statistical improbability.
他们就是想看看
And now they want to see who will be
我们这些幸存者中  谁会是最幸运的那个
the luckiest among the lucky.
您是否有足够强壮的心脏愿意让余无坦博士
Do you have the heart to let Dr. Wootan Yu...
帮您进行改造
help you become a better you?
挑战极限  打开新世界的大门
Open new doors by testing your limits.
不要安于沉闷乏味的现状
Don't settle for a humdrum existence.
尽情享受极致人生吧
Live life to the extreme.
五分钟之内下单
Place your order in the next five minutes
即可免费获得这场人生假期的入场券
and receive a complimentary getaway.
好吧  至少我们知道还剩多久
Okay, well, at least we know how much time we have.
是啊  知道自己的确切死期真是令人欣慰
Yeah, knowing exactly when I'm going to die is a huge comfort.
难道你们还不明白吗？
Do you guys not understand?
他们选中我们  就是想看谁能挺到最后
They chose us to die to see who's the last person standing.
现在需要齐心协力  懂吗？ 帮帮我们
We need you on board right now, okay? Stay with us.
我们不能就这么受他们摆布
We can't just keep playing by their rules.
那你说我们还能怎么办？ 他们在监视我们
What else are we supposed to do? They're watching us.
他们知道我们每一步的行动
They know every move that we're making.
他们在监视我们
They're watching us.
有线索了
I've got something.
都过来  快
Come on, come on.
好了  放这里
I got it. Here, here.
好吧  发现什么了？
Uh. Okay. What do we have?
一个拳头  一根手指  两根手指  可能是
A fist, one finger, and two fingers. It could be...
可能是零一二  对不对？ 像是密码
It could be zero, one, two, right? Right? Like a code.
不不不  是单词
No, no, no. It spells...
E-K-G.
对  这是手语
Yeah, it's sign language.
没错  我表哥失聪  这事他们肯定也知道
Yeah, my cousin is deaf. They must have known about that, too.
这间密室里有没有心电图测量仪？
Is there an EKG machine here somewhere?
你在干什么？
Hey, what are you doing?
根据量子芝诺效应
Quantum Zeno effect. Atoms won't change
原子在被持续观测时不会发生衰变
if you take continuous measurements...
所以只要他们一直监视我们
so as long as they're watching us,
我们就改变不了命运
we can't change our state.
这游戏永远设定成他们赢
The game is designed so they always win.
好好好  可现在我们真的需要你帮助
Okay, okay. We could really use your help right now.
不   我们可以找到别的出路
No. We can find another way out.
现在有什么出路都不知道
We don't even know the first way out.
别乱砸东西了  深呼吸冷静一下
Just stop smashing shit and take a deep breath.
您是否有足够强壮的心脏愿意让余无坦博士
Do you have the heart to let Dr. Wootan Yu...
帮你进行改造
help you become a better you?
佐伊  你得冷静下来
Hey, Zoey, you need to calm down.
有毒
三分钟之后  他们会毒死我们
In three minutes, they're going to poison us.
我们已经没时间了  你快冷静下来
We are running out of time here. You've got to calm down.
你们都别跟我说什么冷静  好吗？
Stop telling me to calm down, okay?
你们根本就不听我说话
You're not listening to me!
你们看  心电图测量仪  它可能就是出去的关键
You guys, it's an EKG machine. Maybe this is our way out.
本  把T恤脱掉  -为什么是我？
- Ben, take your shirt off. - What? Why me?
因为这是下一条线索  就这样
Because it's the next clue, that's why.
快点  就用它测个心率
Come on, it's just an EKG machine.
不  这个鬼地方什么东西都没那么简单
No, no. Nothing is just anything in this hellhole.
心率够高应该就能出去  本
The right heart rate could open a door, Ben.
我们快没时间了  -快点
- We're running out of time. - Hurry up.
测就测  来吧
Just do it. Come on.
快点  按住  深呼吸
Come on. Hold those, hold those. Take a breath, take a breath.
你的心率太低
Your heart rate's too low. Your heart rate's too low.
失败
这根本就没用
It's not working.
你换别人来测吧
Somebody else has to do it.
迈克  心率得高点才行  换你来测
Mike, we need a higher rate. You've got to go.
佐伊
Zoey
什么？ 我又不是小白鼠  要测你自己测
What? I'm not your guinea pig, man. You do it. You try it.
本测了没事  老兄  快
Look. Ben is fine, man. Come on,
不行再换我  我们要高心率  快点
I'll go next. We need a higher rate. Come on.
你简直是疯了
You're going crazy.
行  我来
All right, let's do it.
佐伊求你了  你就听我说两句
Zoey, please, just listen to me for two seconds.
该死
Shit.
这屋子是铜墙铁壁  够了  你这么乱砸没用的
We're in a metal box. Come on, that's not going to help.
别砸东西了  来帮帮我
Just stop smashing shit and help me.
再高点  快
Higher, higher, higher. Come on!
佐伊  求你了
Zoey, please.
不
- No.
挑战极限  打开新世界的大门
Open new doors by testing your limits.
他说挑战极限
Testing your limits. Testing your limits.
你得挑战心率的极限  -你开玩笑
- We need a higher rate. - You're kidding me.
我现在慌得不行
Man, I'm already freaking out here.
心率早到极限了
My heart rate's sky high.
难道再来个立卧撑跳还是开合跳？
Want me to do some burpees, jumping jacks?
你还想让我怎么样？
What do you want me to do?
你用这个吧  -你疯了吧？
- We've got these. - What are you, insane?
海岸警卫队找到我的时候  我都快死了
When the Coast Guard found me dying from hypothermia...
因为我体温太低  心脏都快停跳了
my heart was half dead, man.
是这个  把我给救回来的
These are what they used to bring me back.
医生就是用这个
Come on, this is what they used.
不  这不行
No, no. That is not an option.
好了听着  心率是线索  他们把它放在我的病房
Listen, it is a clue. They put it in my room
因为他们知道我能想到这一点  迈克
because they knew I would know, Mike.
你的心率已经很高了  男人点儿  来吧
Your heart's already high. Man up, come on.
你开什么玩笑? 拿开
Are you kidding me? Get these away from me.
迈克  看着我
Mike, Look at me, goddamn it! Look at me!
再过一分钟  他们就要放毒气了
In one minute, they're about to poison us.
我们都会窒息而死
And we are going to suffocate, all right?
氧气会一点一点耗光
We're going to run out of breathable air,
就像你当初被困在矿井里那样
just like you did in that mine.
该死
Shit.
你想想你弟弟卡尔
You think about your brother, Cal.
他叫卡尔对吧？ 现在你可以赎你的罪了
Cal was his name, right? This is your time.
迈克  只有你能救我们
Mike, you can save us.
只有你能救我们  迈克
This is it. You could save us, Mike.
现在  救我们  -好吧
- Now, save us. - Okay.
动手吧  动手啊  快点  动手
Do it. Do it, do it quick! Come on, do it!
杰森  你在干什么？
Jason, what are you doing?
不
No. No.
不  住手  你走开
- Hey, don't. Stop! - Get off me!
你会杀了他的
You're going to kill him!
失败
不能失败
- Come on!
迈克？ 你干了什么？
Mike? What did you do?
他没呼吸了  迈克
He stopped breathing! Mike!
醒醒  迈克  住手
Wake up! Mike. Hey, stop! Stop!
您是否有足够强壮的心脏
Do you have the heart to
再来
Come on!
愿意让余无坦博士
let Dr. Wootan Yu...
醒醒  迈克
Come on, Mike!
帮您进行改造
help you become a better you?
挑战极限  打开新世界的大门
Open new doors by testing your limits.
挑战极限
Testing your limits.
高和低
High and low. High and low.
见鬼  该死
Goddamn it. Fuck!
该死
Oh, shit.
我不懂该怎么急救
I don't actually know how to do this.
你现在还想干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
挑战极限  也许他们要的是最低心率
Extremes. Maybe they mean the low end.
危险  请勿移动
醒醒
Hey, come on.
醒醒 兄弟
Come on, man.
醒醒
Come on.
迈克
Mike.
恭喜
那扇门  那扇门开了  门开了
The door. The door is opening. It opened.
佐伊
Zoey. Hey!
Zoey!
佐伊  快来  出路在那边
Zoey! Hey, come on. There's a way out.
这个才是出路
This is the way out.
你会窒息的  快点走
You'll suffocate, come on!
你走
Just go!
求你了  -你快走
Please! - Just go!
该死
Shit.
我们该带她一起走的
We should have made her come with us.
我们这是留她在那里等死
We just left her there to die.
这是她自己选的
She made her decision.
你怎么就这么冷血？
What the hell is wrong with you?
刚才到底是怎么回事？
What happened back there?
我保住了我们俩的命  不客气
I saved our asses. You're welcome.
你杀了迈克
You killed Mike.
是整天不运动的生活习惯杀了他
Sitting on his ass 12 hours a day killed him.
就算挺得过这间密室  他也挺不过下一间
If it wasn't that room, it would've been the next.
你对人一向如此对不对？
So that's just something you do, isn't it?
你朋友在船上是怎么死的？
Your friend on the boat?
你想说什么  本？
What are you saying, Ben? Huh?
有话直说吧
Use your words.
你们两个人  只有一件外套
One jacket between the two of you.
把你的外套给我
Give me your jacket!
怎么就这么巧  他直接游走淹死了
It's pretty convenient that he just swam off and died.
刨根问底对你没好处
You don't want to do this, man.
你之所以能幸存  根本不是因为幸运
You being the sole survivor had nothing to do with luck.
承认吧
Admit it.
是你杀了他  承认吧  就是你杀了自己的朋友
You killed him! Admit that you killed your friend.
生还是死  是自己选的
Surviving is a choice!
现在该你选了
- Make yours.
睁大你的狗眼  好好找线索
Keep your eyes open and look for clues.
有船舱门
Hey, it's a hatch.
我们也只能打开了
I guess we just open it.
我们就这么进去吗？
What are we letting in?
行  进就进
Fine, I'll do it.
好重  -少废话  再用点劲儿
It's heavy. - Come on, try harder.
混蛋  我又不是天天泡健身房
Asshole, I don't go to the gym every day.
真是见鬼
Goddamn it.
用力
Come on, come on.
我手上这是什么？
What's this shit on my hands?
我觉得不太对劲
I don't feel so good.
他们在把手上涂了东西
They put something on the handle.
你在融化
Hey, you're melting. You're melting.
什么？ 你在融化
What? - You're melting.
什么？ 等等  你看  上面有字
What? Wait. Look, look. It says something.
想离开  请自便  但友情提示
"Feel free to leave, but may we note...
最好还是先找到解药
it's best to find the antidote."
这什么解药该怎么找？
How the hell are we supposed to do that?
起来找解药  臭小子
Get up and look, goddamn it!
还找什么解药  老兄？ 我们无论如何都得死
Who cares, man? We're going to die here anyway.
我不会死的  我一定不会死
I'm not going to die. I'm not going to die.
好吧
Okay.
在哪里？ 快点  在哪里？
Where is it? Come on. Come on. Where is it?
解药在哪里？ -在哪里？
- Where is this bastard? - Where is it?
本
Ben. Ben.
我找到了  -快给我
- I have the anti... - Give me that!
这是我的
It's mine!
该死
Shit.
Oh, shit.
天啊
Oh, my God.
好了  这里有十个数字  四个空位
Okay, I've got ten numbers, four spots.
要找到四位密码
I need a four-digit code.
进入五号密室  各就各位
Entering room five. Stand by.
已就位
Standing by.
这里有两具尸体  完毕
We have two bodies. Over.
收到
Copy.
二十分钟之内完成清理  完毕
20 minutes for disposal and cleanup. Over.
收到  通话结束
Copy. Out.
看这个  这里有个氧气面罩
Look at that, the oxygen mask.
她用这玩意能干什么？
What the hell was she going to do with that?
呼吸  混蛋
Breathe, bitch!
该死
Shit.
赢家
你确实是匹黑马
Now, you were a dark horse.
我原本赌杰森会赢
My money was on Jason.
可你看这就是密室逃生的迷人之处
But, see, that's why these games are so fascinating.
也不知怎么  你就战胜了火焰
Somehow, after being burnt,
冰雪  毒药  残疾
frozen, poisoned, and crippled...
只要再逃出这最后一个密室就算大功告成
you still managed to escape the final room.
你想过自己还有这种潜力吗?
Did you ever think you had that in you?
这种勃发的冲劲儿以及才智？
That adrenaline, that drive?
坐吧  庆祝一下
Sit down. Celebrate.
你总算做成了一件事
You won something for once.
你就是设计这个杀人迷宫的神经病吗？
So, you're the psycho that designed this murder maze, huh?
不  我是游戏大师
No, I'm the Games Master.
当前叫价
不  我是游戏大师
No, I'm the Games Master.
负责设计的是密室制造者
The Puzzle Maker designs the rooms.
可你拿杀人当消遣  难道看电视还不够你消遣的吗？
But you kill people for fun. There's nothing good left on TV?
你的朋友都被你害死了
You killed all your friends...
就因为你不愿意给他们出一趟打车钱
because you didn't want to pay for a goddamn cab.
我想你还没这个资格指责我  本
I wouldn't get too comfortable on that high horse, Ben.
自人类文明诞生以来
From the beginning of civilization...
我们就知道人类自相残杀谋求生机的过程
we've known there was something captivating...
一直就非常具有观赏性
about watching human beings fight for their lives.
所以我们会看角斗士竞技  会看公开行刑
That's why we watch gladiator games, public executions...
会在高速上探出头去看追尾
rubber-necking on the freeway.
可现在的人太脆弱
But now the world's gone soft.
在哪里都图个安全  干什么都要小心
Everything is safe. Everything is careful.
所以我们才为那些
So, we created a sport for people
骨子里依旧嗜血的人发明了这个游戏
who still have a thirst for savagery...
还为他们提供专属的包厢
and we provided them with a box seat
来观赏这极致的生死大战
for life's ultimate drama.
我们的客户都是
Our customers are some of the most powerful
这世界上最有权势的人
people in the world.
但是他们每年都有新要求
But every year, they demand more.
要更复杂的密室
More complicated rooms.
更有意思的主题
More interesting subjects.
更多生死赌注的玩法
More ways to gamble on life and death.
去年他们要大学生运动员来玩
Last year, they had college athletes...
而前年呢  是学者
the year before, savants...
今年我们找来了终极幸存者
and this year we had lone survivors.
他们想知道运气这东西到底能不能保命
They wanted to know if luck had anything to do with it.
运气好的人才不会被变态绑架和折磨
Lucky people don't get kidnapped and tortured by psychopaths.
你知道叫别人变态
You know, it's kind of hurtful
会伤对方的心吧？
when you call someone a psychopath, huh?
我也觉得这游戏挺蠢
I thought it was stupid, too.
但是再看看你
But here you are...
我们有史以来赢面最小的玩家
our lowest-odds ever to win...
竟然还活着
still alive.
我是真没想到会这样
I really didn't think it was possible...
但我也说了
but as I said...
你的赢面是最小的
you were the long shot.
那我也赢了
So I won.
赢了就能回家  对吗？
That means I get to go home, right?
本
Ben...
你看赛马比赛结束后
at the end of the Kentucky Derby...
得到奖励的是马吗？
do you think the horse gets a prize?
系统过载
赢家
游戏进行中
本
Hey. Hey, Ben.
起来  本  起来
Come on. Hey, Ben, come on. Come on.
本
Ben.
本  快起来  本  快点  起来
Ben, come on, get up. Ben, come on, get up.
不
No!
你走不了  除非游戏结束  佐伊
You can't leave until we finish our game, Zoey.
好了  我们得确保
Okay, we have to make sure that...
他死了
He's dead.
走吧
Okay. Come on. Come on.
快  这里有一部货梯
Come on, there's a service elevator.
赢家
你是回来救我的
You came back for me.
对  我不想再当唯一的幸存者了
Yeah, well, I'm tired of being the only survivor.
佐伊  快走  好的
Zoey, go, go. - Okay.
已经过了二十四小时  他的情况稳定了
It's been 24 hours. He's stable now.
你最好休息一下
You should get some rest.
他准备好了
He's ready.
贝尔医生  请立刻到手术室来
Dr. Bell, please come to the OR.
贝尔医生  请到手术室
Dr. Bell, OR, please.
戴维斯小姐？
Miss Davis?
你现在能跟我走一趟吗？
Are you feeling well enough to come with me?
是  说得对  我们会去做二次检查的
Yeah, you're right, we'll have to check that for roof access.
好了  我们走
All right, everyone, 360.
戴维斯小姐
Miss Davis.
等一下  这里之前是等候室  好吗？
Wait, this was the waiting room. Okay?
它突然变成了一个一个巨大的烤箱  懂吗？
And then it turned into a giant oven, okay?
还有火  火是从天花板上喷出来的
And there was fire. The fire came down from the ceiling.
我们没有找到任何证据能证实你的描述
We haven't found any evidence of the things you've described.
这里  看  这里是通风口
That. Look. This was the duct.
当时上面盖着一幅画
There was a painting that came down.
你以前是不是出现过幻觉？
Have you ever seen things that weren't there before?
这些不是我的幻觉  好吗？
I am not imagining this, okay?
听着  当时本也在
Look, Ben was there, too.
等他醒了  他也会跟你说的
He'll tell you all this when he wakes up.
好吧  你是说你的朋友本·米勒吗？
Right. Your friend, Ben Miller?
我们从医院拿到一份报告
We got a report from the hospital.
本的血液里
They found traces of three different
被检测出了三种违禁药物成分
illegal substances in his bloodstream.
无路逃
"No way out."
戴维斯小姐  -这是易位构词
- Miss Davis. - It's an anagram.
余无坦博士
Dr. Wootan Yu.
您是否有足够强壮的心脏愿意让余无坦博士帮您
Do you have the heart to let Dr. Wootan Yu help you...
无路逃  余无坦
No way out. Wootan Yu.
余无坦就是无路逃  -戴维斯小姐
- "Wootan Yu" is "No way out." - Miss Davis.
无路逃  余无坦
No way out, Wootan Yu.
这个  看  这个就是游戏里的设置
This. Look. That was a part of the game.
这是游戏里的设置
This is part of the game!
我们得撤离大厦了
We've got to vacate the premises.
余无坦
Wootan Yu. Wootan Yu.
六个月后
谢谢
Thank you.
那么  说说你最近怎么样吧？
So, are you going to tell me what's going on?
我最近刚刚升任洛根广场的区域销售代表
I am the new regional sales rep for all of Logan Square.
我要正式对接客户了  虽然只是卖全素狗粮
I'm officially client facing. It's for vegan dog food...
不过  你懂  这是我的新起点
but, you know, you've got to start somewhere.
我非常为你骄傲
I'm really proud of you.
这是家庭作业吗？
Is that homework?
联合车站惊现威尔梅特籍男子尸体
这是什么？
What is this?
迈克·诺兰突发心脏病去世
Mike Nolan died of a heart attack
在联合车站的卫生间里
in a bathroom in Union Station.
杰森·沃克在高速公路上突然摔下摩托车
Jason Walker was thrown from his bike on the I-64...
体内发现残留迷幻药
DMT found in his system.
丹尼·汗  在密歇根湖溺水身亡
Danny Khan drowns in Lake Michigan.
溺亡者尸沉密歇根湖
丹尼·汗  在密歇根湖溺水身亡
Danny Khan drowns in Lake Michigan.
阿曼达·哈珀  独自一人攀岩
Amanda Harper, rock-climbing alone,
毕竟这样才能符合真实死法
because that makes sense...
她是坠崖身亡
falls and dies.
我们原本也会这样上报纸的
There would have been articles for us, too.
这件破事你该翻篇了
You've got to let this shit go.
我们不能当这些人从来没有存在过
I can't just pretend that they never existed.
其他收到游戏邀请的人全都死了
Everyone else who was sent those invitations died...
可发送邀请的人还在逍遥法外
and whoever sent them is still out there.
你不想查清楚吗？ 我们能找到他们
Don't you want answers? We can find them.
他们暗中布局想让我们输  可我们赢了
They rigged the game sothat we would lose and we won.
我们在他们设的局里赢了他们
We beat them at their own game.
我手里没有太多线索  不过
I didn't have a lot to go on, but...
这个标志
the logo...
是不可能存在的物体
it's an impossible object.
艺术家埃舍尔画的无尽的楼梯
It's an Escher staircase that turns in on itself.
它真的独一无二
It's totally unique.
阶梯上的数字是有规律的
The numbers are in a pattern on the staircase.
二十三  二十二  在循环的数列中垂直出现
23, 22 in a repeated sequence of right angles.
这其实是坐标
They're coordinates...
一座无名工业建筑的坐标
for an unlisted industrial building
就在曼哈顿岛上
in the middle of Manhattan.
他们就藏在不远处
They're hiding in plain sight.
知道方位又能怎么样呢?
What are we supposed to do with that?
我订了两张飞机票  -你订了飞机票吗?
- I bought us plane tickets. - Plane tickets?
两周后出发  我要去
Two weeks, I'm going.
佐伊  你是有幸存者的负罪感
Zoey, it's called "survivor's guilt."
我的心理医生说  要想继续生活  你就得往前看
My therapist says that in order to live, you need to move on.
往前看不等于逃避
Moving on doesn't mean running.
我不想再逃了  你去吗？
And I'm done running. Are you in?
好吧
All right.
行  我去  我们走
Yeah, I'm in. Let's do it.
不过我可没有《谍影重重》男主角的能耐
You're not Jason Bourne, though.
能接受吗?
- Okay? - Mm-hmm.
出来啊  肯定在这里
Come on. It's got to be in here.
我找到了  X代表位置
Found it! X marks the spot.
出来  到底在哪里?
Come on, come on, where is it?
就是这个吧?  我找到工具了
This has to be it, right? I've got the tool!
这里  应该能接上我们找到的门闩
Right here. It must connect to the bolt we found.
好的
Okay.
在门上试  看能不能转开
Try it on the door. See if it'll turn.
你可以的
You can do it.
开了吗? -打不开啊
- Anything? - It's not going!
试试能不能转开  -完全转不动
- See if you can turn it. - It's not working!
顺时针转转  -顺时针吗?
- Try clockwise. - Clockwise?
对  顺时针  -好的
- Yeah, clockwise! - Okay.
我飞翔无需翅膀
流泪也无需双眼
跳出来个信息  -什么？
- Something happened here. - What?
近地警告  -这是什么?
Terrain, terrain. - What's this?
糟糕  又是一条谜语
No, it's another riddle.
我飞翔无需翅膀  流泪也无需双眼
"I fly without wings, I cry without eyes."
这是什么意思? -我不知道  让我想想
- What does that mean? - I don't know. Give me a second!
把头低下
Heads down!
准备迫降
Brace for impact!
等等  是云  试试云  -云吗？
- Wait, "cloud"! Try "cloud"! - "Cloud"?
对  是云  -好吧
- Yeah, "cloud." - Okay.
再试试门闩  快点  进去
Try the door! Come on, let's go!
拉起  小心  近地警告  决断高度
Pull up. Caution, terrain. Decision height.
近地警告  拉起
Terrain, terrain. Pull up.
不  快点
No, no! Come on! Come on!
小心  近地警告
Caution, terrain. Terrain, terrain.
做点什么
Do something!
拉起  决断高度  拉起
Pull up. Decision height. Pull up.
模拟结束  需要重置吗?
Ending sim. Do you want to reset?
不必  干得很好  已经可以投入游戏了
No. Good work. We're ready for game time.
那个破门闩又把我的手给划伤了  拉里
I hurt my goddamn hand on that bolt again, Larry.
断开模拟器
Deboard the simulator.
这次的存活率是多少?
What's the probability of survival?
在百分之四左右
It's approximately four percent.
好吧  要是不给她机会  游戏也就不好玩了
Well, it's not a game if she doesn't stand any chance.
伊利诺伊州  驾驶证
佐伊·戴维斯
好吧  要是不给她机会  游戏也就不好玩了
Well, it's not a game if she doesn't stand any chance.
伊利诺伊州  驾驶证
佐伊·戴维斯
我们已经拦截了她的航班信息  游戏开始
We've intercepted her flight information. It's on.
伊利诺伊州  驾驶证
佐伊·戴维斯
伊利诺伊州  非驾驶证
本·米勒
我们已经拦截了她的航班信息  游戏开始
We've intercepted her flight information. It's on.
飞机票/登机牌
佐伊·戴维斯  本·米勒
芝加哥 飞往 纽约
我们已经拦截了她的航班信息  游戏开始
We've intercepted her flight information. It's on.
我非常高兴佐伊克服了她对飞行的恐惧
I'm so glad Zoey got over her fear of flying.
我们再玩一局吧
Let's play again.
译本提供&校订：SWAT1909
英文&时间轴：explosiveskull